Miller, Frank B., Corning Glass files /4259
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frank B. Miller Corning Glass files
1953-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Miller, Frank B.
/4259
2.5 cubic feet
2.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Research on Corning Glass Works done with William Foote Whyte.
8059039
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 25, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Frank B. Miller joined the ILR School faculty in 1954 as an assistant professor after completing his Ph.D. there and undergraduate studies in psychology at Reed College. He became associate professor in 1960 and professor in 1966. During his 31 years as a faculty member, Miller taught courses on a range of subjects, including complex organizations; small groups in industrial organizations; and applied human relations. He also designed the first course on women in the workplace at the ILR School and co-taught it with colleague Alice Cook, a world-renowned expert on issues faced by working women. In addition, Miller chaired the organizational behavior department for several years (1967-69) and served two terms as director of the school's Office of Resident Instruction (1962-67). As a visiting professor at the University of Istanbul in 1960-61, Miller gave lectures that were translated into Turkish and became a textbook for personnel studies courses there. He also contributed chapters to books on industrial sociology and worker incentives and was a fellow of the American Sociological Society and the Society of Applied Anthropology. Although he attained emeritus status in 1985, Miller continued teaching part time at Cornell and Bernard Baruch College in New York City for another 10 years.
Scope and Contents
Research note, correspondence, and article drafts concerning research on the Corning Glass Works in Corning, NY. Included are employee questionaires.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4210: Frank B. Miller Files /4308m: Frank Miller ILR School Poetry /4311: Frank Miller Papers /4331: Frank B. Miller Collections
Miller, Frank B.(Frank Barton), 1921-2006.; Whyte, William Foote, 1914-2000; Corning Glass Works; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8059039
- Corning Glass Works Research July 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Corning Glass Works June 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New Problem x^2 data on Shops, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Interaction Counts - Thompson Miller #8011, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Inter ets. Thompson Miller #7877, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Inter CTS. Gullo # SP837, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Gullo # 8090, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Schroeder Interaction CT # 7726, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Inter cts. Schroeder #SP844, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Inter cts. Schroeder #7826, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Inter cts. Holton #7837, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- S. Gullo #7934, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Interactions - Schroeder, Carlines, Bower, Quintal, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bibliographic Stuff - Master Lists - Thesis Design, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Questionnaire - Letter - Thesis, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Fellowship Application, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Inter. Cts. Gullo #7836, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Corning - Field Notes Atteslander (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Steuben Catalogs (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Expanding the Scope of Case Study Research (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Benton Blowing Road Maps (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Carter Pinelli Data Sheets (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Carter Pinelli Matrices (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Mail to Frank B. Miller, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Core Curriculum Paper (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Quantitative Stuff (Box 1, Folder 26)
- How Much Do You Know About Glass? (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Quantitative Studies of Work Groups (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Quantitative Studies of Work Groups 2 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Quantitative Studies of Work Groups 3 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Corning Book Grist (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Gaffer - Photos of Possible Use of Corning - Steuben People, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Design Policy Within Industry As a Responsibility of High Management (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Literature Society & Personality (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Bundy Tamaqua Interviews, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Human Organization (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Bundy Article, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Foreward-Economic Incentive & Human Relations, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Human Resources - Mail, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Industrial Sociology Chapters, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Professor Gittler - Industrial Sociology Chapter, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- "Resistentialism" Article (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Steuben Morgan Meetings March 1954 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Carbon Copy, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Double Material Pen Copy (Box 1, Folder 45)
- New Design Thesis (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Questionnaire, Letter &; Meeting Notice Final Form, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Questionnaires (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Frank Miller Questionnaires (Box 2, Folder 2)
- "New Look" Shop Interaction Data (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Inter CTs - Holton #856 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Interaction Counts - Schroeder Shop #SP850 Frank Miller - Cornell University (S.E. Ave.) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Situational" Interactions - A Worthwhile Concept (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Corning Glassworks Research May 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Corning Glassworks Research April 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Corning Glassworks Research March 1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Corning Glassworks Research February 1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Corning Glassworks Research January 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Corning Glassworks Research December 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Job Satisfaction & Neutrals (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Union President Marshall Lipton (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Chief Steward George Hart (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Plant Manager - Tom Patten (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Personal Manager Al Bella (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "Situational" Interactions - A Worthwhile Concept?, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Corning Research July 1952 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Corning Research May 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Corning Research April 1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Corning Research (up to) March 1952 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Corning Glassworks Research September 1953 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Situation Interaction Material 1952 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Blowing Room Monograph Ideas (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Corning Glass Works Research November (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Corning Research October 1952 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Corning Research September 1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Corning Research August 1952 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Corning Research June 1952 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Completed Corning Questionnaires 1/3, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Completed Corning Questionnaires 2/3 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Completed Questionnaires 3/3 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Dean Correspondence- J.W. McConnell, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Dean Risley, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Bundy Tubing Company Letters, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Communication Grapevine Mass Media, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Communications Cee-Syracuse Workshop- Secondary School Student Councils (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Cornell University Legislation, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- M.P. Catherwood - Annual Planning Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- M.P. Catherwood- Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Aluminum Company of America, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Arensburg, Conrad, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Argyris, Chris, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Atteslander, Peter- Germany (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence A to Z Inc 1954, 1955, 1956, 1957, 1958, 1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Cognill, Mary Ann, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Editors - Books & Article Ideas, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Letters to Various Editors, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Gubbels, Robert, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- CSSP in a New Location" Bundy Tubing Miller Fuerstenberg 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "Why Don't They Work Harder" Fuerstenberg-Miller (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Landsberger, Henry, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Leslie Company, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lozi, Lunciona, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Miller, F.B. - Letters of Application, etc., 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Sayles, Leonard- Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Turner, Arthur N.- Possible Ph. D, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Walker, Charles, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- University of Washington, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Whyte, William F. - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Wilensky, Harold, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Safety Program - Spring 1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Selection & Assignment GLF Fall 1956 Program (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Sklar, Bernard - Possible PhD Candidate, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Special Committee - Brophy, R. Campbell Follman, F. Miller, Radom, Risley, Trice Corvini, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Rome Conference H.R. Spring '56, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)